□(+1) 678-882-9228 | dingxiong203@gmail.com | #www.cns.gatech.edu/~xiong/ | □ github.com/dingxiong | □ www.linkedin.com/in/xiong-ding

Current Experience

Airhnh Software Engineer San Francisco, CA, USA May. 2017 - Present

Infrastructure team

· Main responsibility:

Build and maintain **Ebert** (the review service) for *airbnb.com*.

Propose and build the next generation of review platform Ebert2.0

Details:

Increase the performance of this service: P95 latency from 85ms to 45ms.

Setup review Elasticsearch cluster for full-text search on reviews on listing pages.

Cooperate with core-storage team to build **review pipeline** to serve review aggregated data, i.e, review count, review overall rating.

Core metrics&features:
— QPS: Average: 10K. Peak: 12K. Traffic comes from room description page, user profile page, checkout page and so on.

Latency: Overall, P95: ~45ms; ~P99: ~80ms; P999: ~250ms. Different endpoints have different latency.

Features: • Mcrouter cache enabled • Horizontal scalable • Accompanied by mutation publisher

• Framework & tools: Dropwizard, Chef, Airflow, Elasticsearch, Mcrouter Cache, Powergrid(multithreading)

Skills

Programming: Proficient: Java; Familiar: C++

Domain knowledge: Numerical PDE, Matrix analysis, Nonlinear dynamics Libraries: Boost.Python, Eigen, ARPACK, OpenMP, OpenMPI, FFTW

Education

Ph.D. in Physics Georgia Institute of Technology Aug. 2012 - May. 2017 Atlanta, GA, USA

· adviser: Prof. Predrag Cvitanović • Research area: nonlinear dynamics, cycle expansion theory, complex Ginzburg-Landau equation

M.S. in Computer Science & Engineering GPA: 3.86/4.0 Georgia Institute of Technology Atlanta, GA, USA Jan. 2016 - Jun. 2016

B.S. in Physics GPA: 3.75/4.0 **Wuhan University** Wuhan, China Sep. 2008 - Jun. 2012

Graduate Courses

Math: Real analysis, Numerical methods for ODEs, Numerical linear algebra

- Physics: Nonlinear dynamics, Statistical mechanics, Quantum field theory
- Computer science: High Performance Computing (HPC), Computational data analysis, Computability&Algorithms

Research Experience

Center for Nonlinear Science, School of Physics, Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA Jun. 2013 - May. 2017

- Research topic: Computation of Floquet vectors in Kuramoto-Sivashinsky system
 - main Result: Find the smallest eigenvalue of Floquet matrix to be order of 10^{-3000} with relative accuracy 10^{-14} .
- tools/skills used: C++, Boost.Python, Boost.Numpy, HDF5, Arpack, Matrix decomposition, Eigen
- Research topic: Investigation of the local dimension of inertial manifolds in chaotic systems
 - main Result: We show strong evidence that the inertial manifold of 1-d Kuramoto-Sivashinsky system has dimension 8.
- tools/skills used: C++, Matlab, Exponential integrators
- Research topic: Symbolic dynamics in symmetry reduced 1-d Kuramoto-Sivashinsky system
- main Result: In the symmetry reduced state space, we propose to obtain the symbolic dynamics of 1-d KS equation by constructing appropriate

Poincaré sections. tools/skills used: C++, Matlab, Eigen, Cycle expansion theory

School of Mathematics, Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA Jan. 2016 - Jun. 2016

- Research topic: Time-step adaptive exponential integrator for soliton explosions in 1d and 2d cubic quintic Ginzburg-Landau systems
 - main Result: Formulize a new time-step adaptive exponential integrator for complex GL equation.
 - tools/skills used: Numerical PDE, C++, Boost, Numpy, Matplotlib

Conferences & Talks

SIAM Conference on Application of Dynamical Systems

Snowbird, Utah, USA Talk: Periodic Eigendecomposition and Its Application in Nonlinear Dynamics Coauthor: Prof. P. Cvitanović

May 2015

Dynamics Days US

Jan. 2014 Atlanta, GA, USA

Poster: Lyapunov exponents, Floquet exponents and covariant vectors in Kuramoto-Sivashinsky equation Coauthor: Prof. P. Cvitanović

Publications

[1] X.Ding, H. Chaté, P. Cvitanović, E. Siminos, and K. A. Takeuchi, Estimating the dimension of an inertial manifold from unstable periodic orbits, Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 024101 (2016)

[2] X. Ding and P. Cvitanović, Periodic Eigendecomposition and its application in Kuramoto-Sivashinsky system, SIAM J. Appl. Dyn. Syst. 15, 1434– 1454 (2016

[3] X. Ding and S. H. Kang, Adaptive time-stepping exponential integrators for cubic-quintic complex Ginzburg-Landau equations, arXiv:1703.09622